João Pedro Peters Barbosa

BRIEF

Power Systems Electrical Engineer graduated from the Engineering Faculty of the Federal University of Juiz de Fora, Minas Gerais. He has programming experience in different programming languages and also modeling and simulation skills in software related to Electric Power Systems. He served as a research student in different projects throughout the undergraduate course and, still as an undergraduate student, carried out an academic exchange semester at Temple University, Philadelphia. He is currently a Master's student in the Graduate Program in Electrical Engineering at the Federal University of Juiz de Fora (PPEE / UFJF). Adventurous into Python programming, following software engineering best practices to improve computational skills. He doesn't mind making mistakes and always seeks to promote a safe work environment, valuing collaboration between peers.

SOCIAL LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joaoppeters/

GitHub: https://www.github.com/joaoppeters

EXPERIENCES

May 2021 – May 2023 Graduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

- Research development in the area of Voltage Stability based on the analysis of steady state of Electric Power Systems.
- Contribution in the development of the Smooth Power Flow formulation.

Mar 2020 – Apr 2021 Undergraduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

- Research development in the area of Distributed Energy Resources (DERs) to provide new services to the electricity grid.
- Research project partnership between UFJF and PETROBRAS.

Aug 2018 - Aug 2019 Undergraduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

• Research development in the area of current control in static buck-boost converters connected to the network.

Aug 2017 – Aug 2018 Undergraduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

• Research development in the area of current control in static converters connected to photovoltaic panel systems.

EDUCATION

May 2021 – May 2023 Masters in Science – Energy Systems, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

GPA: 3.75/4.0

Aug 2015 – Apr 2021 Power Systems Electrical Engineering Undergraduate, Juiz de Fora, MG IRA: 78.47/100 Aug 2019 – Dez 2019 UFJF Academic Exchange Semester, Temple University Philadelphia, PA GPA: 3.74/4.0 Jul 2018 – Dez 2018 Technical Qualification, SENAI Juiz de Fora, MG **SKILLS Leadership and Teamwork Microsoft Office, Latex Organization and Efficiency** Python, MatLab, C, C++ Flexibility and Adaptability ANAREDE, ANAFAS, ANTEM OpenDSS, PSIM, OpenModelica Analytical skills and of Problem solving Git **LANGUAGES** French **Portugues Native Basic Fluent English** German **Basic** Spanish **Basic CERTIFICATES** 2021 Graduate Record Examinations (GRE) – Educational Testing Services (ETS) 2021 **TOEFL iBT – Educational Testing Services (ETS)** 2020 Data Analysis with Python – freeCodeCamp 2020 Introduction to Git and GitHub - Coursera 2019 Modeling and Simulation of Distribution Systems Using OpenDSS – UFJF 2016 Certificate of Advanced English (CAE) – University of Cambridge First Certificate of English (FCE) – University of Cambridge 2014

REWARDS

2022

Best Article Master's Category

IX Simpósio Brasileiro de

Sistemas Elétricos (SBSE)

Avaliação e aprimoramento de metodologias para representação de CER no problema de

	fluxo de potência		
2017	Best Article Undergraduate's Category	XIV Congresso Brasileiro	
		de Eletrônica de Potência	
		(COBEP)	
	Design and implementation of a predictive current controller applied to regulate a battery bank's power flow connected to a DC microgrid		
2016	Best Article Undergraduate's Category	XXII Seminário de Iniciação	
		Científica da UFJF (SEMIC/UFJF)	

Síntese de conversores MMC para aplicação em sistemas de geração fotovoltaicos e sistemas de transmissão em corrente contínua

SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS			
2022	Avaliação e aprimoramento de metodologias para	IX Simpósio Brasileiro de	
	representação de CER no problema de fluxo de potência	Sistemas Elétricos (SBSE)	
2020	Síntese de conversores MMC para aplicação em sistemas	PRINCIPIA, v.19	
	de geração fotovoltaicos e sistemas de transmissão em		
	corrente contínua		
2017	Design and implementation of a predictive current controller	XIV Congresso Brasileiro	
	applied to regulate a battery bank's power flow connected to	de Eletrônica de Potência	
	a DC microgrid	(COBEP)	

PROJECTS

PowerFlow: development of Python code to support students and researchers in studies of steady state analysis of electrical power systems, based on reading data from ANAREDE files.

INTERESTS

Involving electrical power systems: static and transient analysis, voltage stability, mathematical modeling of electrical equipment, operation, optimization, planning, distributed energy resources **Involving programming:** online learning, reinforcement learning, optimization techniques, software engineering best practices, open-source project development, machine learning, artificial intelligence